手续办得还顺利吗？
Did everything go okay with the annulment?
没问题，都办好了 罗斯，谢谢你
No problems. It's all taken care of.Ross,thank you.
你们要不要去看电影 好啊
Want to go see a movie?Yeah,why not?
我去穿毛衣 好
I'll get my sweater.
想不想听一件奇怪的事？ 时刻准备着
Want to hear something weird?Always.
我没去办注销
I didn't get the annulment.
什么？ 我们还是夫妻
What?We're still married.
不要告诉瑞秋，待会见
Don't tell Rachel. See you later.
你有口香糖吗？
Do you have any gum?
等等！ 罗斯，可以跟你谈一下吗？
Wait! Wait! Ross,can I just talk to you for just a second?
但是电影快开演了
We'll be late for the movie.
那里有计程车，计程车
There's a cab. Taxi!
来得正好，上车吧
That's great.My God,huh? There you go.
我们走着去就行了，就在前面的安洁丽戏院
We're gonna walk. It's right at the Angelika.
安洁丽戏院，开车
The Angelika! Go! Go!
你没去注销？ 我知道
You didn't get the annulment?!I know.
罗斯 我试过，但在律师楼我只听到
-Ross？-I tried,but when I got to my lawyer's office,all I heard was:
“离婚三次，离婚三次”
"Three divorces! Three divorces!"
没错，是女高音
Yes,in that high voice.
我不希望我的墓碑上刻着 “罗斯盖勒，离婚三次”
I just don't want my tombstone to read: "Ross Geller: Three Divorces."
你不必担心那个 你爱刻什么就刻什么
Don't worry about that. Your tombstone can say whatever you want.
你可以刻 “罗斯盖勒，婚姻高手”
It can say,"Ross Geller: Good at Marriage."
我的会刻 “菲比布菲，活埋在此”
You know? Mine's gonna say,"Phoebe Buffay: Buried Alive."
反正我不能再添一次失败婚姻
All I know is,I can't have another failed marriage.
所以你要娶个不知情的女生？
So you're gonna be married to a girl who doesn't even know about it?
是“女人”，抱歉
Woman. Sorry.
我还没想好要怎么做 拜托你先别告诉瑞秋
Okay,so I don't have it all worked out quite yet.Just don't say anything to Rachel.
瑞秋是我最要好的朋友之一
Rachel is one of my closest friends.
不过当唯一知情的人感觉不赖 好吧
But being the only one that knows about this makes me feel special. Okay.
停车
Okay,stop,stop!
菲比？ 瑞秋
Phoebe?Hey,Rach!
你在搞什么？ 抱歉，弄错了
What was that?Sorry. Mix-up.
电影好看吗？ 我还没看
How was the movie?I haven't seen it yet.
那就要快了 安洁丽戏院，开车
You'd better hurry. The Angelika! Go!
不…
No
本集播出：“罗斯拥抱瑞秋”
The One Where Ross Hugs Rachel
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
等我们同居 我可以买一台泡泡糖机吗？
When I move in,can I get a gumball machine?
当然可以，乔伊不让你买？
Of course. Joey wouldn't let you have one?
对，他对甜食要求特别严
No,when it comes to sweets,he's surprisingly strict.
你想好要怎么说了吗？ 还没，我试了好几次
Did you tell him you're moving out?No,I keep trying.
我只能说出“乔伊，我得…”
And I can get out,"Joey,I have to.."
然后就退缩改说“去上厕所”
Then I lose my nerve and I finish with,"go to the bathroom."
他可能以为我有病
He may think I'm sick.
我真的得告诉瑞秋了
I have to tell Rachel,but....
这件事不能再拖了
We just gotta get it over with.
下次见到他们，我们就说
Next time we see them,we'll just tell them.
就这么决定
That's it.
以后你都要这样指使我是吧？
That's how it'll work now? You'll just order me around?
差不多 好
-Pretty much. -All right.
莫妮卡
Monica
你有没有好一点？
Hey,man,you feeling better?
乔伊，我们有事要说
We have something to tell you.
天哪，你怀孕了
Oh,my God!You're pregnant!
不是
No!
没有吧？不是
No？No！
乔伊，是这样的
Look,Joe,here's the thing.
莫妮卡和我决定在这里同居 所以我会搬出来
Monica and I have decided to live together,here.I'm gonna be moving out,man.
我真替你们高兴 恭喜，再见
I'm really happy for you guys. Congratulations. See you later.
等等，乔伊，你还好吗？
Are you okay?
很好，我得走了，我有戏要演
I gotta go. I've got an acting job.
你们会信才怪
Like you'd believe that.
讨厌啦
This sucks!
我只是要搬到对门，我保证
I'll be across the hall. And I promise you...
莫妮卡和我一分手 我就回去跟你住
the minute Monica and I break up,I'm moving right back in.
就现在好了？
Maybe that's now.
好，如果你要跟他住 我有责任揭穿他的真面目
If you're gonna move in with him...I feel it is my responsibility to tell you the truth about him.
他是个很烂的室友
He's a terrible roommate. Terrible.
他会忘记…他老是…
He forgets to....He always,he always....
我骗谁啊，他最棒了
Who am I kidding? He's the best roommate!
菲比
-Hey,Phoebe. -Hey.
有一篇文章在讨论 结了婚却不告诉对方的人
Oh,look,here's an article about people who marry people and don't tell them.
真的？ 对，我在看罗斯盖勒杂志
-Really? -Yeah,I'm reading Ross Geller Magazine.
菲比，你有看到瑞秋吗？
Have you seen Rachel?
没有，怎样？ 我有个好消息
-No,why? -I have some exciting news.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
不是，钱德和我决定同居 太好了
No!Chandler and I are moving in together.Oh,that's good!
不过如果你有宝宝要叫什么？ 提示：菲比
But if you were pregnant,what would you name it? Hint,Phoebe.
怎么了？
What's up?
钱德和我要住在一起
Chandler and I are moving in together.
天哪 我妹妹和我的死党…搞在一起
Oh,my God.Oh,my little sister and my best friend...shacking up.
太好了
That's great. That's great.
喂，我也很高兴 好，一起来
Guys,I'm happy too.Okay,come here.
今天真热闹 有人要同居，有人办注销
Big day,huh? People moving in. People getting annulled.
我要去找瑞秋了，不过…
I gotta go find Rachel.
你们能不能先灌些坏消息给她 减轻一些冲击？
If you see her,give her some really bad news,so mine doesn't seem so bad.
讲给瑞秋听的坏消息…
Something bad to tell Rachel.
什么是她的坏消息？
Bad news for Rachel. What could that be?
你能不能别再提了？
Can you just lay off,please?
我的人生很难堪 我应该去住在别人的楼梯底下
My life is an embarrassment. I should just go live under somebody's stairs.
根本没那么严重
It's not that big a deal.
离婚三次又怎样 你还是会有私生活、会约会…
You'll have been divorced three times.You'll have a life,you'll date..
才不会 我的约会指数降到谷底
No,I won't. I'll be at the bottom of the dating barrel now.
比我低的只有离婚四次的人 杀人犯和…
The only guys below me will be Four-Divorce Guy...Murderer Guy
地质学家
and geologists.
罗斯，你别傻了 你可爱聪明又体帖
Ross,you're being ridiculous. You are cute and smart and sweet.
这比离婚三次重要多了
That is much more important than three stupid divorces.
是吗？ 你交过离婚三次的男朋友吗？
Have you dated anyone who's been divorced three times?
这样问不公平 离三次婚的人通常都60岁了
That's not fair. Most guys that have been divorced three times are 60.
你多年轻啊
You're young.
我是很年轻
That's true,I am young.
也许吧
Well....
只有你自己在意 什么难堪都是你在想像
Nobody cares about this except you.This embarrassment thing is all in your head.
我证明给你看
-Here,I'll show you.
过来 干嘛？
Come here. -What?
我朋友罗斯即将三度离婚 但你们会和他约会吧？
Hi. My friend Ross is about to be divorced for the third time.But wouldn't you date him?
你们稍候，我去找罗斯来
And if you wait right here,I'll go get Ross.
我还以为你是瑞秋 我哪里露出破绽了？
Thought you were Rachel.What gave me away?
我得赶快告诉她
I gotta tell her.
我已经告诉罗斯和菲比 只剩她了
I told Ross and Phoebe. She's the only one left.
所以大家都知道了 我们确定要同居了，不能反悔
It's official. We're moving in together.No turning back.
你怕吗？怕吗？
Are you scared? Are you?!
不怕
No.
那是我最可怕的声音 你真勇敢
That was my scariest voice. You're brave.
今天真惨
The worst day.
你以为自己终于受重视了 结果老板却把你的名字叫成瑞寇
You're finally making progress at work,then your boss calls you Racquel.
我进公司前4年 大家都叫我夏拉拉
Listen,for the first four years of my work,everybody called me Sha-la-lap
是真的 我相信
-Seriously. -I believe you.
当时正在开员工大会 当然不会有人纠正她
It was in the middle of a meeting,so no one wants to correct her.
于是大家都叫我瑞寇
So everyone's calling me Racquel.
到了下班前 收发室的人已经叫成洛基了
By the end of the day,the mailroom guys were calling me Rocky.
我还是觉得你很好很漂亮
Well,I still think you're very,very nice and very pretty.
什么？
What?
交给你了
All yours,babe.
坐
Have a seat.
听我说 钱德和我要一起住在这里
Listen,Chandler and I...are going to live together…Here.
天哪，真是太棒了
Oh,my God.That's so great!
我真替你们高兴
I'm so happy for you guys!
真的？
Really?
你真好，还先问我
And that was so sweet of you to ask.
天哪 我们三个在一起一定会很开心
The three of us are gonna have such a good time living together!
是啊
Yes,we are.
钱德，你早上不能慢慢冲澡了 因为瑞寇不能迟到
Chandler,you'll have to watch those long showers you take...because you know Racquel can't be late.
瑞秋 他会注意的
He'll work on that.
好兴奋喔
This is so exciting!
来敲我的门 （《三人行》主题曲）
Come and knock on our door
我们等着你
We'll be waiting for you
一旦知道内情就没那么糟了
See? Once you know the stories,it's not that bad.
第一次，老婆隐瞒性向 不是我的错
First marriage: Wife's hidden sexuality. Not my fault.
第二次，宣誓时叫错人 有一点点是我的错
Second marriage: Said the wrong name at the altar.A little my fault.
第三次
Third marriage:
怎么能让脸上涂鸦的醉鬼结婚 内华达州的错
They shouldn't let you get married...when you're drunk and have writing on your face.Nevada's fault.
你们觉得怎样？谁会没兴趣？ 谁会不想和他约会？
So what do you think,ladies? Who wouldn't want to date him?
离婚无所谓，我会和他约会 但他得先恢复自由身
The divorces don't bother me. I'd date him.But not while he's still married.
那你呢？你也想吧？
And you,wouldn't you want to date?
事实上我再也不约会了
I'm not dating at all anymore.
我老是看上对我不好的男人
I was only dating guys that were bad for me.
在我解决这个… 随便啦
So I decided that..Good. Good. Whatever.
梅格你呢？
And you,Meg?
我也不在意离婚的事 但我不会和他约会
Well,I don't care about the divorces,either.But I wouldn't date him.
他平常不会流这么多汗
Normally,he doesn't sweat this much.
他显然还爱着这个瑞秋 什么？
It's just that he's obviously still in love with this Rachel girl.What?
她说 “他显然还爱着这个瑞秋”
She said,"He's obviously still in love with this Rachel girl."
别乱说 没错，瑞秋是我的好朋友
This is crazy. I mean,yes,Rachel is my good friend.
我过去确实爱过她 但现在她只是我的妻子
And I have loved her in the past...but now,she is just my wife.
菲比，帮我说句话好吗？
Phoebe,will you help me out here?
你娶她时我也以为你爱她
Well,I thought you loved her when you married her.
我们喝醉了 喝那么多我连乔伊都会娶
We were drunk! I would've married Joey with that amount of alcohol.
你做的比乔伊崔比亚尼烂多了
You could do a lot worse than Joey Tribbiani!
很抱歉，但是你们错了 我只是不想离三次婚
I'm sorry,but you guys are wrong.I just don't want to be divorced three times.
没错，他以此为借口不想离婚 因为他爱她
Now he's using this three-divorces reason...because he wants to stay married to her because he loves her.
我必须说：梅格，干得好
I must say,well done. Bravo,Meg.
好，如果你们这么想 那我就不管什么三次离婚了
Fine. If this is what you think,forget about...the whole three-divorce thing.
我现在就去找律师办注销
I'll go to my lawyer's office right now and get this marriage annulled.
因为我一点也不爱她 一点也不爱
She means nothing to me.Nothing!
现在是你的神经质让我发毛
Okay,now I wouldn't date you because you seem a little creepy.
我突然觉得他好有魅力
I am so attracted to him right now.
我们什么时候要跟瑞秋说实话
When will we tell Rachel what actually will happen?
快了，我刚才说不出口 你也看到乔伊多难过
Soon.I just couldn't before. You saw how upset Joey got.
我不忍心伤害我最好的朋友
I couldn't do it. She's my best friend.
乔伊也是我最好的朋友
Joey's my best friend.
我不是吗？
I'm not your best friend?
你自己刚才说…
You just said..
你当然是
Of course you're my best friend.
但请你告诉瑞秋好吗？
Would you tell Rachel?
好啦，至少我现在有准备 好
All right. At least I'm prepared.
漂亮
Oh,yes.
不是给你的，你有不开心吗？ 现在有了
-They're not for you. Are you upset? -I am now.
嗨，室友 好，再见
Hey,roomie.Okay,bye.
瑞秋，我有重要的事要告诉你
There's something important I have to tell you.
你怀孕了？
Are you pregnant?
没有，但我要扔掉这件衣服
No,but I'm throwing this shirt away.
刚才有一些误会
I think there was a little misunderstanding before.
我说钱德和我想住在一起
When I said that Chandler and I wanted to live together...
意思是只有我们两个人
we meant alone together.
天哪，真好笑，我居然会误会
Oh,my God. That's funny. I can't believe I did that.
不，是我不好，我没说清楚 真的很抱歉
No,sweetie. You know what? This is my fault.I wasn't clear.I'm really sorry.
你可以慢慢找房子 一点也不用急
Listen,you take as much time as you need to move out,okay?There's absolutely no rush.
好
Okay.
Okay
你不吃饼干吗？
Don't you want a cookie?
好啊
Sure.
谢谢 需要面纸吗？
Thanks.Do you need a tissue?
这是哪里的饼干？ 我做的
-Where did you get these? -I made them.
天哪，真好吃
Oh,God,they're so yummy!
这是谁的？ 我的
-Okay,whose is this? -That's mine.
那这个呢？ 也是我的
-And what about this? Whose is this? -That's mine.
那这罐洗碗精呢？
Okay,whose dishwashing soap is this?
我们搬进来时就有了
That was here when we moved in.
难怪浓成这样
Oh,I guess it really is concentrated.
以后我回家你就不在了
It's gonna be weird when I come home and you're not here.
没有乔伊和钱德家了 没有乔和钱家了
No more Joey and Chan's.No more J and C's.
“要不要去乔伊和钱德家？” “不行，已经不在了”
Want to go to Joey and Chandler's? Can't. It's not there.
我只是搬到对面 我们还是可以跟以前一样
I'll be across the hall. We can still do all the same stuff.
但以后就不能半夜起来 促膝长谈感觉和未来了
We won't be able to have those long talks at night...about our feelings and the future.
我们一次也没做过
Not once did we do that.
不是有一次很晚了，我不舒服
Don't you remember that night,it was late and I was feeling sick...
你说我“明天”就会好一点？
and you said I would feel better tomorrow?
对，我记得
Oh,yeah. I remember that.
我会想念那些事 我也是
I don't know. I'm just gonna miss living with you.Yeah,me too,man.
那是什么？ 好恶心
-What the hell is that? -That's disgusting.
我告诉瑞秋我们要自己住了 是吗？她还好吗？
I told Rachel that it's just gonna be the two of us.Oh,yeah? Well,how'd she take it?
非常好，令人意外的好
Really well.Surprisingly well.
没有哭，也没有生气或难过
She didn't cry. She wasn't angry or sad.
你很不爽没把最好的朋友弄哭？
And you're upset because you didn't make your best friend cry?
我只求一点真情流露 我们6年室友耶
All I'm asking for is a little emotion.Is that too much to ask after six years?
我们没你们要好吗？ 没你们开心吗？
What,are Rachel and l not as close as you guys?I mean,did we not have as much fun?
我不值得她掉几滴泪吗？
Don't I deserve a few tears?
乔伊一听到就哭得死去活来
When we told Joey,he cried his eyes out.
我才没有哭得死去活来
I did not cry my eyes out!
这就像一个时代的结束 再也没有乔兄和钱哥了
Come on,it's like the end of an era.No more J-Man and Channy's!
我一定要问 有谁那样叫我们？
Okay,I gotta ask,who calls us that?
你又结婚了
You got married again?
对
Yes.
这是你2年内第二次结婚
So that's your second marriage in two years?
对，2年两次，总共三次
Yes. Second in two years.Third,overall.
罗斯，我当了23年离婚律师 没有一个客户比你捧场
I have been a divorce attorney for 23 years...and never have I had so much business from one client.
告诉我怎么回事
Why don't you tell me what happened?
基本上，瑞秋和我在拉斯维加斯 我们喝醉了…
Basically,Rachel and I were in Vegas,and we got drunk.
抱歉，她就是你上次结婚 叫错名字的那个瑞秋？
I'm sorry,is this the same Rachel whose name you said...at the altar in the second marriage?
对，但是我并不爱她
Yes,yes,yes.But I do not love her.
这就好多了
That's better then.
这只是酒醉犯错，我要办注销 我懂了
This was just a drunken mistake,and I need to get it annulled.I see.
你考虑过接受治疗吗？
Have you considered therapy?
我想今天办注销就好了
I think just the annulment for today.
要填几份表格 简单
-There are some forms to fill out. -Easy.
必须有证人证明 你们当时神智不清
We'll need witnesses who can testify that you were not of sound mind.
没问题
No problem.
你和瑞秋得向法官说明
We'll need you and Rachel to testify before a judge.
不能不找她吗？ 我已经告诉她事情都办妥了
There's no way to do this without her?Because I kind of already told her it was taken care of
你当然这么说
Of course you did.
罗斯，你和瑞秋都在场 才能办理注销
Look,you can't get an annulment unless you and Rachel are both there.
那找一个长得像瑞秋的人呢？
What about someone who looks like Rachel?
我会考虑接受治疗
I will think about the therapy.
我想我们应该开始分东西了
So I was thinking that maybe we should start dividing up our stuff.
好
Okay.
没必要拖拖拉拉的
No point in dragging it out.
我是说你搬走我们分开的事
Dragging out the long process of you moving out...and us not living together anymore.
好
Okay
瑞秋，这个要归谁？
What about this? Who gets this?
我不知道我想不想要 它有太多回忆
I don't know if I want it because it might be too many memories.
那是什么？ 我不知道
-What is that? -I don't know.
瑞秋，大盘子呢？ 我要你留着大盘子
How about this? I want you to have the big plate.
谢谢，我很喜欢这个盘子
Wow,Monica,thanks. I love this plate.
这样你就会记得我
Something to remember me by.
你又不是快死了 我只是要搬出去
Mon,you're not dying. I'm just moving out.
我们还是会天天见面
We're gonna see each other all the time.
但这是个大转变 也可以说是一个时代的结束
But still,it's a big change.The end of an era,you might say.
你还好吗？眼睛都没眨
Are you okay? You're not blinking.
我很好 我只是在想一个时代要结束了
I'm fine. I was thinking about how it's an end of an era.
好吧
Oh,all right.
但老实说 6年应该称不上一个时代
But I gotta say,I don't think six years counts as an era.
一个时代就是一段重要的日子
An era is defined as a significant period of time.
我觉得重要 或许你不觉得重要
It was significant for me. Maybe it wasn't significant to you!
你是怎么了？ 你才怎么了？
-What is the matter with you? -What is the matter with you?!
你为什么没有更不开心？ 我们要分开了你不难过吗？
Why aren't you more upset?Aren't you gonna be sad that we're not living together?
你都不会想我吗？
Aren't you gonna miss me at all?
好吧，说出来你别生气
Monica,all right. But don't get mad at me.
我只是有点难以相信 难以相信什么？
It's just a little hard to believe.What's hard to believe?
你们啊，你们就是这样
I mean,it's you guys. You do this kind of stuff,you know?
你们在拉斯维加斯说要结婚又不结了
You were gonna get married in Vegas,and then you backed out.
我并不认为你们会真的同居 对不起
I'm not upset because I don't see you going through with it. I'm sorry.
瑞秋，事情已经确定了 钱德会搬进来
It's going to happen.Chandler will move in here.
但是… 你先听我说完
-But I.. -I know,just let me finish,okay?
这不是在拉斯维加斯的一时冲动 我们真的想要住在一起
This isn't something that we just impulsively decided to do in Vegas.This is something that we both really want.
我们会住在一起 是吗？
And it is going to happen.It is?
真的？ 没错，亲爱的
Really?Yeah,sweetie.
我们不能再住在一起了？
You mean,we're not gonna live together anymore?
不行了
No
天哪，我会好想你 我也是
Oh,my God. I'm gonna miss you so much.I'm gonna miss you.
这是一个时代的结束 我知道
I mean,it's the end of an era!I know!
再见 又来了
-Okay,bye. -Oh,no.
你去办注销了吗？ 我办不了
So did you get the annulment?-I couldn't.
我就知道，因为你爱瑞秋
-I knew it. Because you love Rachel.
不是那样的 事情比想像中复杂…
It's not that. Annulments are more complicated..
爱让它变得复杂
Complicated because of the love.
我不爱瑞秋
I do not love Rachel.
我现在就去告诉她 好尽快把手续办好
I'm telling her about the whole thing...so we can get this marriage annulled as fast as possible.
我如果爱她会这么做吗？
Would I do that if I loved her?
我现在更确信你爱她
I've never been more convinced of your love for her.
我对瑞秋没有感觉，好吗？
I do not have feelings for Rachel,okay?
怎么了？
Oh,what's wrong?
莫妮卡和钱德真的要同居了 我得搬出去，一切都要变了
Monica and Chandler are moving in here...and I have to move out and everything is changing.
过来，别难过，一切都会好起来的
Oh,my God,come here,come here. It's okay.Everything's gonna be okay.
谢谢你 不客气
-Thank you. -Of course.
罗斯和瑞秋结婚了 莫妮卡和钱德差点结婚
So Ross and Rachel got married.Monica and Chandler almost got married.
我们要不要也搞在一起？
You think we should hook up?
要，但不是现在
Oh,we do.But not just yet.
是吗？那是什么时候？
Really? Well,when?
好，首先钱德和莫妮卡会结婚 还会发大财
Well,first Chandler and Monica will get married...and be filthy rich,by the way.
但婚姻会破裂
But it won't work out.
天哪 是啊
Wow. I know.
然后我会为钱嫁给钱德
Then I'll marry Chandler for the money.
你会娶瑞秋生几个漂亮小孩 太好了
And you'll marry Rachel and have the beautiful kids.Great.
接着我们就抛弃他们结婚
But then we ditch them and we get married.
我们会有钱德的财产 瑞秋的孩子
We'll have Chandler's money and Rachel's kids.
监护权很好抢，因为瑞秋酗酒
Getting custody will be easy because of Rachel's drinking problem.
那罗斯呢？ 我不想多说，不过…
What about Ross?I don't want to go into the whole thing.But
我们吵架，我杀了他
we have words and I kill him.